<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1-0-0 on CYF&#43;</title>
    <link>/versions/1-0-0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1-0-0 on CYF&#43;</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/versions/1-0-0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Sprint 5</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-5/</guid>
      <description>Study Distributed Systems: Asynchronous Work and Pipelines Troubleshooting Primer Projects RAFT OTEL Do the raft-otel project. This large project explores a distributed consensus protocol using distributed tracing. Product https://github.com/orgs/CodeYourFuture/projects/19/views/6?filterQuery=+-status%3ABacklog%2CDone+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Sprint 4</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-4/</guid>
      <description>Study Distributed Systems: Asynchronous Work and Pipelines Troubleshooting Primer Projects Kafka Cron - Distributed Cron system with Prometheus monitoring Troubleshooting project #4 TOADD Product https://github.com/orgs/CodeYourFuture/projects/19/views/6?filterQuery=+-status%3ABacklog%2CDone+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Sprint 3</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-3/</guid>
      <description>Study Distributed Systems: State Troubleshooting Primer Linux Bash I &amp;amp; Linux Bash II (There are other blog posts in the same series that could be useful to go through in spare time, would recommend running the commands that the blog post suggests for better understanding.) PHP fastcgi - https://www.php.net/manual/en/install.fpm.php Systemctl - https://www.freedesktop.org/software/systemd/man/systemctl.html and then https://www.redhat.com/sysadmin/linux-systemctl-manage-services Nginx https://nginx.org/en/docs/ https://nginx.org/en/docs/http/request_processing.html https://www.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/examples/phpfcgi/ Projects Multiple servers Revisit Troubleshooting project #3 TOADD Optional (but recommended) software ops tutorials: Do this HashiCorp tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Sprint 2</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-2/</guid>
      <description>Study Distributed Systems: State Troubleshooting Primer Projects Batch processing Buggy app Memcache Troubleshooting project #2 TOADD Product https://github.com/orgs/CodeYourFuture/projects/19/views/6?filterQuery=+-status%3ABacklog%2CDone+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Sprint 1</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-1/</guid>
      <description>Study Distributed Systems: Reliable RPCs Troubleshooting Primer Linux process Intro Linux Process and Signals - This doc has some commands to give you an insight on how to view processes and pass signals to a process; we recommend running those commands and documenting your learning. Projects Servers &amp;amp; databases Multiple Servers Docker &amp;amp; Cloud Deployment gRPC Troubleshooting project #1 TOADD Product https://github.com/orgs/CodeYourFuture/projects/19/views/6?filterQuery=+-status%3ABacklog%2CDone+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYF&#43;01 Prep Workbook</title>
      <link>/workbooks/workbook-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workbooks/workbook-0/</guid>
      <description>Prep The CYF+ Immersive Engineering Programme is an intensive three month course. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to get through and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to hit the ground running. To prepare for this exciting opportunity, you will:
Linux Take this Unix 101 course (and then try 102) Print out this Linux-Cheat-Sheet Go Learn the basics of the Go programming language: Get Started - The Go Programming Language Read this, you might find it useful for working through your first projects: How to use the fmt package in Golang And optionally Learn Go with tests Projects Complete the prep and first two projects from the Immersive Go course</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
