<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on Syllabus</title>
    <link>/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on Syllabus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS &amp; DynamoDB Workshop</title>
      <link>/workshops/aws-dynamodb-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/aws-dynamodb-workshop/</guid>
      <description>What we will learn today?
Databases overview MongoDB Mongo Shell Mongo with Node Before we start Download and install MongoDb from https://www.mongodb.com/download-center#community. Follow the instructions for your platform (Windows, Linux or OS X).
Also download and install RoboMongo from https://robomongo.org/download.
Open two instances of terminal. Run mongod—this will start MongoDB then run mongo on the other window.
In the mongo shell (terminal), run the command version() and you should get the version of Mongo printed on the terminal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>/workshops/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/interviews/</guid>
      <description>There are many kinds of interview. We have workshops to help prepare you for some of them:
Interview type Technical Interviews </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Testing Workshop</title>
      <link>/workshops/js-testing-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/js-testing-workshop/</guid>
      <description>What will we learn today? Tracing Code Testing Unit Testing Unit Testing Frameworks - JEST Test-driven Development More on Testing Test coverage Refactoring Modules Fork and Clone the js-exercises-tdd repo
Tracing Code What is Code? Computer code is a set of rules or instructions. It is made up of words and numbers and when you put them in the right order it will tell your computer what you want it to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB 101</title>
      <link>/workshops/mongodb-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/mongodb-101/</guid>
      <description>What we will learn today?
SQL vs NoSQL Why MongoDB? Mongo Shell Basic Commands MongoDB administration Aggregation Replication Sharding What&amp;rsquo;s next? Before we start Download and install MongoDB from https://www.mongodb.com/download-center#community. Follow the instructions for your platform (Windows, Linux or OS X).
Open two instances of terminal. Run mongod in the first instance - this will start MongoDB.
In the second instance, first download the sample data script: curl https://gist.githubusercontent.com/agiamas/35b2b954cc942f95709273d3cb9d2cf3/raw/b1bb399942dab287832d41b3b75f6b54c6f00bb1/mongodb_data.js &amp;gt; mongo_data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/workshops/accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/accessibility/</guid>
      <description>Content Week 1. Intro to Accessibility 2. Accessibility for Devs Learning Objectives In this series of workshops we cover the following Learning Objectives
1. Intro to Accessibility Participants will be able to:
List the 4 main groups of disabilities (visual, hearing, motor, cognitive) Define what accessibility is Recall some specific conditions for each categories Define what an invisible disability is and give some examples Define situations where you can experience an accessibility issue, for touch, see, hear and speak or a combination of more than one of them (could be done as coursework) List some reasons why accessibility is important to consider Illustrate what each letter in SCULPT mean Apply advice to check colours and give good text links and alt texts Create an alternative text when sharing photo on social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing.js Workshop</title>
      <link>/workshops/processing-js-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/processing-js-workshop/</guid>
      <description>If you enjoyed using JavaScript to make drawings and animations, we recommend further study and play with the almost identical p5.js library. It&amp;rsquo;s better.
Where to start coding with p5.js We recommend the site called OpenProcessing - it makes it easy to click &amp;ldquo;new sketch&amp;rdquo; and start immediately Alternatively, here&amp;rsquo;s a starting sketch that defines functions the way you have learned so far If you want to use CodePen, here&amp;rsquo;s a p5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
