<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finalprojects on Syllabus</title>
    <link>/finalproject/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finalprojects on Syllabus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/finalproject/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>External Projects</title>
      <link>/finalproject/external-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/external-projects/</guid>
      <description>At CodeYourFuture we try to find interesting, tech-for-good projects that stretch the abilities of our trainees whilst helping an NGO or Charity solve a business problem they are facing.
If you are one of these charities, or know one we could work with, you can find more information below.
Past Projects Here are examples of web apps we built as a Final Project:
Over The Line with The Compass Collective Chatterbox Talents The Breteau Foundation Akwaaba You can find example project briefs on the Project Brief page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project - Week 1</title>
      <link>/finalproject/week-1/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/week-1/lesson/</guid>
      <description>import Feedback from &amp;ldquo;@theme/Feedback&amp;rdquo;;
Overview Welcome Getting Setup Agile Development What is Agile Development? What is a Product Manager? Daily Stand-ups Sprints Mid-week Check-ins What are we going to build? Sprint Planning Exit criteria and tracking the trainees work Welcome 1. Getting Setup (15 minutes) Once you have your team and your assignment, start by sorting out the basic administrative requirements.
1.1. Introductions Before we introduce ourselves let&amp;rsquo;s introduce one of the tools we&amp;rsquo;ll be using to collaborate during the project, Miro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project - Week 2</title>
      <link>/finalproject/week-2/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/week-2/lesson/</guid>
      <description>import Feedback from &amp;ldquo;@theme/Feedback&amp;rdquo;;
Overview Demo Retrospective User research Sprint Planning Technical Support Cooling periods Demo (60 minutes) Led by Trainees, presented back to the class
Integrate all of your work together and share your progress so far with the mentors.
Your presentation should last no more than five minutes and could include:
Slides detailing what you&amp;rsquo;ve done this week UI/UX designs of your project A video of your project A live example of your project If you want to prepare a quick presentation you can use this template</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project - Week 3</title>
      <link>/finalproject/week-3/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/week-3/lesson/</guid>
      <description>See Week 2 for instructions for this week. You are working as a team to deliver a product, so will continue using that format through the Final Projects
Overview Check In Reminder about the tracker and exit criteria Check In: how are the contributions of all team members so far? Here&amp;rsquo;s what we expect: It&amp;rsquo;s important to evaluate our contributions to the group.
A full stack developer must deliver features that touch each part of the stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project - Week 4</title>
      <link>/finalproject/week-4/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/week-4/lesson/</guid>
      <description>See Week 2 for instructions for this week.
Make sure to check in again on the contributions per team members, as detailed on Week 3
Each team must fill out their handover document once they have finished the final project development. This document is important to ensure the Product Owner and technical team that would continue working on this product has all necessary information about what has been done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Preparation</title>
      <link>/finalproject/prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/prep/</guid>
      <description>Checklist to organise Final Projects Getting the Final Projects ready is not a task that can be done a week before the module. A lot of decisions have to be made beforehand, so this high-level list of the steps Volunteers and PROM (Programme Managers) should do in order to get everything ready for Final Projects. It also has the main links of important documents.
When you are on the React Module</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Roles</title>
      <link>/finalproject/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/roles/</guid>
      <description>In the Final Project we have several roles that volunteers and trainees should adopt.
These roles should in total create a balanced team. Each team must have at least one of each of the below roles.
Volunteer Roles Product Manager / Scrum Master Full role description of roles
Your main role is to coordinate the team and make sure everyone knows what they are working on. They can provide support in:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Projects</title>
      <link>/finalproject/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/intro/</guid>
      <description>Learning Goals During the Project you will work on your technical and communication skills. At the end of this module you&amp;rsquo;ll learn the following:
Technical skills:
How to build a complete full-stack application Understanding how each part of an application relates to each other What it means to work on a feature How to work with Git in a team setting How to write readable code Communication skills:
How to communicate effectively with team members Keeping track of your project&amp;rsquo;s progress Knowing if you understand what&#39;s asked of you How to communicate with non-developers about what you&amp;rsquo;re doing Learning how to be solutions-oriented How to work in a Agile setting Objectives The final projects form the final module of the course, comprising four weeks following the completion of the last teaching-based module (currently the database module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Day</title>
      <link>/finalproject/demoday/practice-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/demoday/practice-day/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>/finalproject/demoday/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/demoday/preparation/</guid>
      <description>Learning Outcomes By the end of this session you will be able to
Describe what Demo Day is and what will happen on the day List the aims of the Demo Day presentations Build a presentation that will impress employers Write a description about yourself that is succinct and memorable Highlight what makes a presentation good or bad Use software to create videos of your projects to ensure your presentation goes smoothly Slideshow What is Demo Day?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Briefings</title>
      <link>/finalproject/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/finalproject/projects/</guid>
      <description>New for 2023 Tip of our Tongues Good PR In A Class of Our Own Careless Whisper Study Buddies Jobs From The Boards Hub Planner A Set 2022 Deskeando We are here STAR Logistical Lunch Development Planner Energise! Goal! &amp;lt; 2021 Glossary Class Behaviour Register Feedback Tracker Quiz App Slack Dashboard Class Planner Q &amp;amp; A Graduate Directory Knowledge Checklist Language Exchange Website </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
